Luke Deen Taylor

ABOUT

I've been interested in creating with code since my first LEGO robotics projects as a little kid. I picked up Python in middle school, then turned to the web to share my creations with the world. In high school, I started working with JavaScript and CSS for fun, and eagerly expanded my skills until I'd mastered modern web development. Today, I pair this expertise with skills in interface design and back-end development to bring projects I'm passionate about to life.

EXPERIENCE

Johns Hopkins Coronavirus Resource Center

May-Sep 2020 | Full-Stack Software Engineer | Remote

- Worked as one of three core developers maintaining and expanding coronavirus.jhu.edu, a crucial public health resource drawing 15 million weekly visitors.
- Created rich visual data displays that are cited daily by The Washington Post, NPR, and others.
- Led effort to centralize data processing strategy; singlehandedly developed Python data science toolkit upon which the site's primary engagements are built.
- Oversaw and led development on a major redesign and a full rewrite of the site in Next.js.

JumboCode

Oct 2019-Present | Engineering Lead | Tufts University

- Work on a student team to develop web applications pro-bono for nonprofit organizations.
- Create and lead instructional workshops to teach web development with React.
- Perform project management duties: write and assign tickets; monitor the progress of a year-long project.

Tufts University Digital Services

Oct 2019-Present | Developer | Medford, MA

- Manage multiple weekly alumni outreach campaigns.
- Develop, revise, and send HTML emails with cross-client support to a large audience.

Moonfarmer

Jun 2018-Present | Junior Web Developer | Kingston, NY

- Work on developer team building large-scale React apps and meeting deadlines.
- Switch rapidly between multiple concurrent agile client projects, tracking billable hours on each.
- Write extensive internal technical documentation, as well as public-facing technical blog articles.

Newburgh Armory Unity Center

2017–2019 | Classroom Assistant | Newburgh, NY

 ○ Volunteered teaching basic programming skills to underserved elementary school students.

AppMobi Inc.

Jun-Aug 2016 | Summer Intern | Poughkeepsie, NY

⊕ Built and deployed mobile apps using Angular.js

ORIGINAL WORK

Codus.io

2018-2019 | Vue, Express, Docker

High school independent study project designing and developing a web app for computer science students and classrooms that presents a set of original practice problems in a custom online development environment.

sleep later

2018 | JavaScript, Vue.js, Airtable

Designed and built a fully custom e-commerce front-end, back-end, and CMS for a local clothing startup.

Wikipedia Map

2016 | JavaScript, Node.js, Flask

Web app allowing users to explore the world's knowledge based on related topics. Leverages Wikipedia API to parse articles and extract "related concepts" from relevant page links in order to build a content graph.

EDUCATION

Tufts University

2019-Present | B.S. Computer Science | 3.98 GPA

New Paltz Central High School

2015-2019 | 99.4 GPA

Stanford Summer Institutes

2017 | Artificial Intelligence

SKILLS

JavaScript

Expert-level development skills in web programming with "vanilla" JavaScript as well as with React and Vue.

React	Next.js	Vue	TypeScript	Node

UI/UX Design

Creating interface designs for web apps that are simultaneously beautiful, responsive, and intuitive.

Sketch	Figma	(CSS layout		CSS animation				
SASS	Photoshop		Illustrator		Affinity				

Other technologies

Python Pandas		6	Flask		С	C++		[Docker	
Git	Gr	GraphQL		Asana		GitHub		Jir	а	

CONTACT

- ☑ luke.deentaylor.com
- ☑ luke@deentaylor.com
- github.com/controversial
- dribbble.com/controversial
- **&** 845 943 9304